So now you have filtered your point cloud data and wrote
a RANSAC plane filtering algorithm to remove the table from your scene.
However, thus far, you have been relying solely on object shapes to perform segmentation.
That's right. Even though we've been dealing with point clouds,
your dataset still contains feature rich color information as well that can be
combined with your shape information to perform more complex segmentation tasks.
In this lesson, we'll be introducing a technique called Clustering that will
allow you to segment objects in your point cloud without having to assume a model shape.
In essence, this technique will allow you to find points in
your data set that are clustered together based on particular features.
These clusters could be based on color,
position, texture or a combination of many features.
Performing segmentation using clustering,
it gives you the freedom to discover
an arbitrary number of objects of any shape in your data.