Any and every sensor,
whether related to perception or not,
measures some physical quantity either directly or indirectly.
But these measurements often deviate from
the ground truth due to factors like noise and distortion.
This inconsistency can be attributed to
the measurement system itself or external factors.
We can alleviate external noise,
to some extent, by using various filtering techniques.
But to remove systematic inconsistencies,
we first need to understand their origin or the root cause.
First of all, let me make it clear that no sensor is perfect.
We, humans, have flaws and so do the devices we create.
Two sensors from the same manufacturer may produce
slightly different results due to minor internal variations.
Many sensors show a change in response with changes
in weather conditions like temperature or humidity.
Moreover, some sensors drift naturally with time and, hence, are imprecise.
So, then, how do we deal with this mountain of
inconsistencies to obtain the best possible results?
The answer to that question is calibration.
Calibration at its core is the process of comparing two measurements,
a standard or ground truth and a measurement from the sensor being calibrated.
After the conversion is made,
we can adjust the sensor so that
its measurement matches the ground truth as closely as possible.
Next, you will learn in detail about different types of
calibration and perform a calibration of your RGB-D camera.