At this point you should have a sense of what type of
3D perception sensors are used in robotics,
along with some of their advantages and disadvantages.
As I mentioned before among all the different 3D sensors,
RGB-D cameras stand out as providing the best of both worlds.
With the best of RGB-D camera that provides,
a feature rich color video stream,
and an active depth sensor,
that provides a relatively accurate per pixel depth map for any given scene.
In addition RGB-D cameras are typically cheaper than other 3D sensors like lidars,
time of flight cameras,
or even stereo cameras.
Almost all RGB-D cameras have a USB based plug and play interface,
making them easy to use and accessible to hobbyists, and experts alike.
These sensors are perfect for applications
like indoor autonomous navigation on a mobile robot,
3-D workspace mapping with a robotic arm,
object detection and tracking,
facial recognition and much more.
So let's explore 3-D perception techniques using RGB-D cameras.